Guide to the Robert Summers papers, 1956-1982 RL.11816
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert Summers papers
1956-1982 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Summers, Robert, 1922-2012
RL.11816
0.5 Linear Feet
Robert Summers (1922-2012) was an economist and worked as a professor of economics at the University of Pennsylvania. This collection consists of selected writings and personal items.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Summers (1922-2012) was an American economist. He received a B.A. from the University of Chicago and he completed his Ph.D. in economics at Stanford University. Summers taught at Yale Univesity from 1952-1959 and the University of Pennsylvania thereafter until his retirement in 1991. Summers is noted for his research on international price comparisons and contributions to the Penn World Tables and International Comparison Program, one result of which was the development of purchasing power parity (PPP).
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Robert Summers papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019 as part of the Anita Arrow Summers papers.
Related Materials
Anita Arrow Summers papers, Paul A. Samuelson papers, and Kenneth J. Arrow papers.
Collection Overview
The Robert Summers papers document a selection of his academic and professional writings. The collection provides an overview of Summers's writings on macroeconomics, inflation, national income accounting, capacity utilization, and econometrics. Summers's writings also document his collaborations with other prominent economists, including Lawrence R. Klein and Thomas Marschak.
Summers is noted for his research on international price comparisons and his contributions to the International Comparison Program and the widely used Penn World Tables.
Along with his own scholarship, the collection documents Summers's familial connections to other prominent economists: his wife Anita Arrow Summers, his brother Paul A. Samuelson, his son Lawrence H. Summers, and his brother-in-law Kenneth J. Arrow.
Economics -- United States; Inflation (Finance) -- United States; Macroeconomics; National income -- Accounting; Econometrics; Baseball -- Economic aspects -- United States; Wages; Summers, Anita A.; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009; Arrow, Kenneth J. (Kenneth Joseph), 1921-2017; Summers, Lawrence H.; Klein, Lawrence R. (Lawrence Robert), 1920-2013; University of Pennsylvania. Dept. of Economics; University of Chicago. Dept. of Economics; Stanford University. Dept. of Economics
- A New Set of International Comparisons of Real Product and Price Levels, 1988 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Reprint of article.
- A Peek at the Tradeoff Relationship Between Expected Return and Risk, 1967 (Box 1)
  Includes reprint of article.
- An Econometric Investigation of the Lifetime Size Distribution of Average Annual Income, 1956 (Box 1)
  Includes discussion paper.
- Baseball Production Functions Revisited, 1978 (Box 1)
  Draft paper.
- Clippings, undated (Box 1)
  Copy of newspaper clipping featuring picture of Summers, son Lawrence Summers, brother Paul A. Samuelson, and brother-in-law Kenneth J. Arrow.
- International Price Comparisons Based Upon Incomplete Data, 1973 (Box 1)
- New Insights Into the Structure of the World Economy, undated (Box 1)
- Proposal for Inflation Protection Under the Agreement Between Medicorp-Iran, Inc., and the Ministry of Health, Iran, undated (Box 1)
  Includes draft proposal related to hospital construction.
- Strategy for R&D, 1967 (Box 1)
  Co-authored book.
- Wharton Index of Capacity Utilization, 1966 (Box 1)
  Includes co-authored book.
- World Product and Income, 1982 (Box 1)